<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-08-21T00:19:24+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Manlin Zhang</title><subtitle>University of California, San Diego</subtitle><author><name>Manlin Zhang</name></author><entry><title type="html">Major Website Update: Mobile Optimization &amp;amp; Dark Mode</title><link href="/website-mobile-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Major Website Update: Mobile Optimization &amp;amp; Dark Mode" /><published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/website-mobile-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/website-mobile-update/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="major-website-update-mobile-optimization--dark-mode">Major Website Update: Mobile Optimization &amp; Dark Mode</h1>

<p>I’m excited to announce that my personal website has undergone a major update! This update focuses primarily on comprehensive optimization for mobile user experience and visual comfort.</p>

<h2 id="comprehensive-mobile-optimization">Comprehensive Mobile Optimization</h2>

<h3 id="responsive-navigation-bar">Responsive Navigation Bar</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Brand New Mobile Topbar</strong>: Replaced the original sidebar with a more intuitive navigation experience on mobile devices</li>
  <li><strong>Smart Icon Navigation</strong>: Uses emoji icons instead of text to save screen space</li>
  <li><strong>Adaptive Layout</strong>: Automatically adjusts navigation item spacing and size based on screen dimensions</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="mobile-typography-optimization">Mobile Typography Optimization</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Title Hierarchy Optimization</strong>: H1-H6 headings automatically scale down on mobile for better readability</li>
  <li><strong>Extra Small Screen Adaptation</strong>: Further optimized font sizes for devices under 480px</li>
  <li><strong>Responsive Spacing</strong>: Automatically adjusts page element spacing on mobile</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="technical-implementation-highlights">Technical Implementation Highlights</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Force Hide Desktop Sidebar</strong>: Ensures no layout conflicts occur on mobile</li>
  <li><strong>JavaScript Responsive Detection</strong>: Dynamically detects screen size and switches navigation modes</li>
  <li><strong>CSS Priority Management</strong>: Uses <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">!important</code> to ensure mobile styles are properly applied</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="-dark-mode-support">🌙 Dark Mode Support</h2>

<h3 id="dark-theme-adaptation">Dark Theme Adaptation</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Auto System Preference Detection</strong>: Supports <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">prefers-color-scheme: dark</code> system settings</li>
  <li><strong>Gradient Background Optimization</strong>: Uses softer gradient colors in dark mode</li>
  <li><strong>Text Contrast Optimization</strong>: Ensures readability in dark mode</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="visual-experience-enhancement">Visual Experience Enhancement</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Soft Shadow Effects</strong>: Gentle shadows that reduce visual fatigue</li>
  <li><strong>Smooth Transition Animations</strong>: All interactive elements have fluid transitions</li>
  <li><strong>Consistent Color Scheme</strong>: Maintains visual consistency between dark and light modes</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="-technical-improvement-details">🔧 Technical Improvement Details</h2>

<h3 id="file-structure-optimization">File Structure Optimization</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Added <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mobile-fix.css</code> specifically for mobile styling</li>
  <li>Refactored <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sidebar.sass</code> to support responsive layout</li>
  <li>Optimized JavaScript logic in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_includes/sidebar.html</code></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="performance-optimization">Performance Optimization</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>CSS On-Demand Loading</strong>: Mobile styles load only when needed</li>
  <li><strong>Reduced Reflow/Repaint</strong>: Optimized CSS animations and transitions</li>
  <li><strong>Touch-Friendly Design</strong>: 44px minimum touch target size</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="-mobile-testing-recommendations">📱 Mobile Testing Recommendations</h2>

<h3 id="responsive-testing">Responsive Testing</h3>
<ol>
  <li>Test page layout across different screen sizes</li>
  <li>Check navigation bar display on various devices</li>
  <li>Verify font size and spacing adaptations</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="functional-testing">Functional Testing</h3>
<ol>
  <li>Test all navigation link functionality</li>
  <li>Check touch interaction smoothness</li>
  <li>Verify dark mode switching effects</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="-future-plans">🚀 Future Plans</h2>

<ul class="task-list">
  <li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" />Add touch gesture support</li>
  <li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" />Optimize mobile image loading</li>
  <li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" />Implement PWA functionality</li>
  <li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" />Add more interactive animations</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p>This update represents a significant leap forward in my website’s mobile experience, while also providing a better browsing experience for users who prefer dark mode. If you encounter any issues or have suggestions for improvement, please feel free to provide feedback!</p>

<p><em>Update Date: August 20, 2025</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Manlin Zhang</name></author><category term="Website Updates" /><category term="UI Improvements" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Major Website Update: Mobile Optimization &amp; Dark Mode I’m excited to announce that my personal website has undergone a major update! This update focuses primarily on comprehensive optimization for mobile user experience and visual comfort. Comprehensive Mobile Optimization Responsive Navigation Bar Brand New Mobile Topbar: Replaced the original sidebar with a more intuitive navigation experience on mobile devices Smart Icon Navigation: Uses emoji icons instead of text to save screen space Adaptive Layout: Automatically adjusts navigation item spacing and size based on screen dimensions Mobile Typography Optimization Title Hierarchy Optimization: H1-H6 headings automatically scale down on mobile for better readability Extra Small Screen Adaptation: Further optimized font sizes for devices under 480px Responsive Spacing: Automatically adjusts page element spacing on mobile Technical Implementation Highlights Force Hide Desktop Sidebar: Ensures no layout conflicts occur on mobile JavaScript Responsive Detection: Dynamically detects screen size and switches navigation modes CSS Priority Management: Uses !important to ensure mobile styles are properly applied 🌙 Dark Mode Support Dark Theme Adaptation Auto System Preference Detection: Supports prefers-color-scheme: dark system settings Gradient Background Optimization: Uses softer gradient colors in dark mode Text Contrast Optimization: Ensures readability in dark mode Visual Experience Enhancement Soft Shadow Effects: Gentle shadows that reduce visual fatigue Smooth Transition Animations: All interactive elements have fluid transitions Consistent Color Scheme: Maintains visual consistency between dark and light modes 🔧 Technical Improvement Details File Structure Optimization Added mobile-fix.css specifically for mobile styling Refactored sidebar.sass to support responsive layout Optimized JavaScript logic in _includes/sidebar.html Performance Optimization CSS On-Demand Loading: Mobile styles load only when needed Reduced Reflow/Repaint: Optimized CSS animations and transitions Touch-Friendly Design: 44px minimum touch target size 📱 Mobile Testing Recommendations Responsive Testing Test page layout across different screen sizes Check navigation bar display on various devices Verify font size and spacing adaptations Functional Testing Test all navigation link functionality Check touch interaction smoothness Verify dark mode switching effects 🚀 Future Plans Add touch gesture support Optimize mobile image loading Implement PWA functionality Add more interactive animations This update represents a significant leap forward in my website’s mobile experience, while also providing a better browsing experience for users who prefer dark mode. If you encounter any issues or have suggestions for improvement, please feel free to provide feedback! Update Date: August 20, 2025]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to My Blog</title><link href="/welcome-to-my-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to My Blog" /><published>2024-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/welcome-to-my-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="/welcome-to-my-blog/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my new blog! I’m excited to start sharing my journey in data science, machine learning, and the various projects I’m working on.</p>

<h2 id="what-to-expect">What to Expect</h2>

<p>In this blog, I’ll be writing about:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Data Science Projects</strong>: My work on machine learning models, data analysis, and insights</li>
  <li><strong>Academic Journey</strong>: Experiences as a Master’s student at UCSD</li>
  <li><strong>Personal Projects</strong>: Side projects and experiments I’m working on</li>
  <li><strong>Life Lessons</strong>: Thoughts on balancing work, study, and personal interests</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="recent-work">Recent Work</h2>

<p>I’m currently focused on voice recognition and applying machine learning to ecological problems. It’s fascinating how we can use technology to better understand and protect our natural world.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more posts coming soon!</p>]]></content><author><name>Manlin Zhang</name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to my new blog where I'll be sharing thoughts on data science, machine learning, and life experiences.]]></summary></entry></feed>